- hi my name is Joe brewer and this is
my video recording for the gifted
citizen fellowship application and I'm
wanting to give you just a brief
introduction to what I mean by culture
design and the need for creating a
globally focused research foundation to
guide the formation of a science of
intentional social change so in in
really simple terms think of it this way
that there is a convergence of crises in
the world there are many things
happening to our communities at all
scales as we're going through a cascade
of disruptions in the world and at the
same time there's this massive body of
knowledge skills solutions and insights
that are out there in the world but
they're not properly combined and
communicated in a way that people can
take them and apply them to the process
of social change so right now there is a
desperate need for humanity to
collectively get its act together to
deal with the planetary crisis of global
warming wealth inequality political
corruption massive poverty starvation
etc the planetary scale the more local
scale we have things like you know high
school dropout rates math of addiction
and suicide depression people that are
going on pathways to radicalization and
extremism due to a variety of social
factors and what's interesting is when
we step back and ask what is known about
each of these problems we start to
discover that in the cognitive and
behavioral sciences in prevention
science and public health research in
evolutionary studies in various places
the solutions already exist but they're
not being brought together and applied
similarly when we look at the social
change practices we see if there are
scenario planning there are different
management tools that exist different
ways of facilitating groups to achieve
desired goals and there we see that
there all of these tried-and-true
programs techniques
models solutions but they're not being
brought together in a strategic manner
to guide the process of social change so
what I'm proposing to do is to create a
research foundation that does three
things the first thing that it'll do is
it will coordinate integrative research
agendas for design research and action
research for applied solutions and these
will bring together the research
community to synthesize knowledge and
apply it to social change with
practitioners in the communities working
on social change and also set up
cultural monitoring and tracking
processes for those social change
practitioners to have researchers
studying the culture as it's changing
and getting feedback to help them
understand what's working and what's not
and the second thing that this research
foundation will do is it will set up a
massive open access database so anyone
doing social change work will be able to
have the monitoring and analysis that's
done the data that's gathered be put
into a common database so that best
practices can be created from looking at
across a wide diversity of projects that
will grow and populate the ecosystem of
this community over time now the third
thing that this project will do is it
will create a series of culture design
labs which is a small number of focused
projects that will become case studies
for the design science of intentional
social change over the next three years
and then these case studies will become
demonstrative of what is possible when
we take an integrative approach to
creating a design science for social
change now why is this so essential now
I think that the answer that is fairly
obvious but I'll step out and give a
big-picture point of view for how I see
this change happening so first of all we
have this convergence of crises in the
world that threaten the viability of our
civilization we literally could collapse
or planetary civilization in the next
few decades so now let's kind of go
forward in time and say what would
happen what needs to happen in the year
2050 for us to avoid systemic collapse
well basically in 2050 we would need to
have and
all infrastructure in the built
environment and all of our social
practices built about around biomimicry
principles and regenerative design
basically we have to undo all of the
damage we do between now and then and
then be sure that we're operating in
harmony with nature from then forward
but to have all of that happening by
2050 let's use a signature number here
which is that many of our large-scale
infrastructure projects take 20 years to
build so that means that for us to have
gotten to 100% biomimicry in
regenerative design in 2050 by 2030 we
have to be sure that everyone graduating
from universities with advanced degrees
and professional master's programs and
PhDs or being trained in regenerative
design and biomimicry in whatever field
that they're in well for us to have that
happen in universities by 2030 that
means that by around 2020 we have to
establish a core set of practices and
demonstration sites that become case
studies for best practices to emerge and
to propagate across our universities and
professional domains throughout the
2020s so what that tells us is that
between now in the middle of 2016 and
around 2020 we need to create this
series of case studies and demonstration
projects so that they can propagate
across our educational systems
throughout the next couple of decades so
that by the middle of the century we are
guiding and increasingly shaping or
planetary civilization in ways that
aren't harmony with the planet and this
is something that might seem grandiose
in ambitious and unrealistic but I would
argue exactly the opposite that there
are mountains and mountains of
scientific knowledge and literally
hundreds of fields showing us that only
this scale of an effort is going to be
sufficient to deal with the scale of the
problems that we have to tackle as the
seven point four billion of us alive on
the planet today so the small part that
I'm wanting to do and then I'm applying
for this fellowship for is to
demonstrate that a design science of
likeness is possible that all the pieces
exist and that we can bring them
together organize a
in the next three to five years and I'll
close with one statistic that is
demonstrative for me makes me feel this
is really doable and if we were to ask
the question what percentage of a side
of the world scientists live today and
someone has done this actually as you
can google it 90% of all scientists who
have ever lived or alive
right now and this is the cumulative
result of population explosion plus the
explosion of literacy and education
around the world so we are now
generating more scientific knowledge in
a 12 month period than we did in the
first 300 years of science so the scale
of knowledge that is available to us is
immense and huge in deeply inspiring
what we're lacking is the active
curation in synthesis in application of
all of this knowledge to tackle our
problems in real time and so what I'm
setting out to do is create a
foundational globally focused
organization that will begin the process
of demonstrating this for the rest of
humanity so I would love for us to go on
this journey together let's join forces
and let's change the world thank you